<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biological Metamaterials for Influencing Cell Behaviour</title><link>/research/biological-metamaterials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/biological-metamaterials/</guid><description>An electron micrograph showing silicon nanostructured with high-aspect-ratio nanostructures. I use nanostructured surfaces to study cell response to different microenvironments. I work with high-aspect-ratio nanostructures. These are surfaces patterned with tall and spiky structures.
I explore how varying design parameters such as the pitch and sharpness influences the response of different cell types. The aim is to both understand how the cell&amp;ndash;material microenvironment influences behaviour, and to explore the structure-property relationships of biomaterials.</description></item><item><title>Science in the Supermarket</title><link>/engagement/super-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engagement/super-science/</guid><description>Photograph of engagement stand inside a supermarket in the West Country. Science in the Supermarket was an engagement project, funded by Imperial College London&amp;rsquo;s Societal Engagement Seed Fund to promote studying STEM subjects to young families in the West Country.
Visit the project website
Target audience The campaign targeted families with low science capital to promote the acceptance rates of students from these backgrounds into higher-education programmes. Science capital is a concept developed through the ASPIRES research project into young people’s aspirations, and is defined as “science-related qualifications, understanding, knowledge (about science and ‘how it works’), interest and social contacts (e.</description></item><item><title>Scientists not the Science</title><link>/research-culture/scientists-not-the-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research-culture/scientists-not-the-science/</guid><description>Interviewing the Institute of Physics outreach team at The Cally Festival in 2015. I am fascinated by the way science operates. The nature, topics and goals of research are intrinsically linked to the scientists carrying out the work. Since 2015, I have been investigating these connections through my podcast Scientists not the Science.
What does it mean to be a scientist? Scientists not the Science is a podcast which interviews the people responsible for defining science as we know it: the students, staff, technicians, journal editors, journalists, engagement professionals and science comedians.</description></item><item><title>Organic Bioelectronics for Biosensing</title><link>/research/organic-bioelectronics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/organic-bioelectronics/</guid><description>Illustration of the current range of organs being investigated by the organic bioelectronic community. I explore the use of conjugated polymers to develop a new types of biosensor and biointerfaces. My primary focus is developing a new type of biosensor for use in the early detection of breast cancer.
I use conjugated polymers (plastics that can semi-conduct electricity) to build devices that interface with cells, tissues and biological fluids.</description></item><item><title>STEM Outreach</title><link>/engagement/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engagement/outreach/</guid><description>Alongside my own project, Science in the Supermarket, here is a selection of projects I have been involved in.
Public talks BSA British Science Festival 2019 Daphne Oram Award Lecturer, British Science Festival Presented research at the British Science Festival 2019, as a British Science Assocation Award Lecturer
Science Communication and Public Engagement during a Global Pandemic Invited to talk to Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia (iit) alumni community about the challenges, opportunities and responsibilities of delivering public engagement during a global pandemic</description></item><item><title>Down to Earth</title><link>/engagement/down-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engagement/down-to-earth/</guid><description>I was commissioned by The Naked Scientists to produce a mini-series of episodes exploring different space-technology spin-offs, called Down to Earth. Each episode explores how a technology that was originally developed for space exploration became useful in life on the planet. Episodes were broadcast in the UK on BBC Radio and internationally as part of the main radio show.
Links to online episodes Launch of Down to Earth mini-series How Space Science Gave Us&amp;hellip; Airbags, 27/06/2017</description></item><item><title>Image-Based Cell Profiling and Data Analysis</title><link>/research/image-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/image-analysis/</guid><description>I work with large microscopy datasets and image-based cell profiling tools to automate the process of analysing hundreds of thousands of cells. I work extensively in the R programming language to develop data analysis pipelines that can clean, transform and model large datasets to generate meaningful outcomes.
Quantifying the response of cells to high-aspect-ratio nanostructures Illustration of cell-based image profiling approach. To uncover the complexity of cellular response to high-aspect-ratio nanostructures, I construct image analysis pipelines.</description></item><item><title>Energy Harvesting Organic Diodes</title><link>/research/energy-harvesting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/energy-harvesting/</guid><description>Photograph of organic diodes capable of energy harvesting at 13.56 MHz I worked as a Research Associate in the lab of Professor Henning Sirringhaus at the University of Cambridge from 2015 to 2016. My research focused on understanding and applying organic materials in the context of printed and flexible electronics. I developed organic rectifiers for use in smart packaging.
Developing energy harvesting circuits for smart packaging Energy harvesting circuits (circuits which convert radio waves into power) are found in identity cards and contactless payment systems, as well as in livestock and inventory tracking tags.</description></item><item><title>Organic Transistors and Complementary Circuits</title><link>/research/organic-transistors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/organic-transistors/</guid><description>I undertook my PhD research in the lab of Professor Alasdair Campbell at Imperial College London, from 2010 to 2014. I developed high-speed organic transistors and complementary circuits on plastic. My work used a combination of multiple types of lithography, gravure and inkjet printing.
Listen to me talk about the use of lithography and graphics arts methods in electronics on the podcast Handmade with Dr Anna Ploszajski:
Self-aligned, megahertz switching organic transistors Illustration of self-aligned transitor process.</description></item><item><title>Deceleration Beamline</title><link>/research/deceleration-beamline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/deceleration-beamline/</guid><description>As an Erasmus student, I helped simulate and construct a particle decelerator. This was a deceleration beamline for highly charged ions, as part of the Heidelberg Electron Beam Ion Trap (EBIT), at the Max-Planck-Institut für Kernphysik, Germany. I worked under the supervision of Apl. Prof. Dr. José Crespo López-Urrutia.
Understanding the origin of x-ray emission from comets Image reproduced with permission © Elsevier 2010. Figure showing the presence of charged species generated by the experiment The solar wind is a stream of highly charged ions flowing across the solar system, originating from the sun&amp;rsquo;s corona.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Below is a brief summary of my employment history and education, please contact me for a full CV. My publication list is available via Google Scholar or ORCID.
Employment Assistant Supervisor, Research Associate
Department of Materials / Bioengineering
2016 – present
Research Associate, Organic Diodes for Energy Harvesting
Cavendish Laboratory
2015 – 2016
Research Assistant, Gravure Printed Organic Transistors
Blackett Laboratory
2014 – 2014
Beamline Technician</description></item><item><title>Contact Form</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>Want to know more?
Reach me via this form, or Twitter @StuartGHiggins, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be in touch.
Name E-mail address Message Send Powered by Un-static Forms</description></item><item><title>Contact Form</title><link>/contact_success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contact_success/</guid><description>Thank you for your message.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Laboratory Notebooks</title><link>/research-culture/electronic-laboratory-notebooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research-culture/electronic-laboratory-notebooks/</guid><description>An Electronic Laboratory Notebook (ELN) is a piece of software that allows lab notes to be recorded digitally, rather than using a traditional paper notebook. As a long time ELN user and System Administrator, I explored the considerations around implementing an ELN in an academic setting as part of a published review into their use.1
Ultimately, ELNs can save researchers significant amounts of time and provide a framework for better data sharing between colleagues, collaborators, and different generations of scientists.</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/teaching/</guid><description>Supervision Receiving the President&amp;#39;s Medal for Outstanding Assistant Supervision from Imperial&amp;#39;s Provost, Professor Ian Walmsley. I am formally recognised by Imperial College London as an Assistant Supervisor, working with five students within the Stevens Group. Previously, I supervised two MSci students within the Department of Physics, Imperial College London
My role includes designing projects, working alongside and mentoring students through their PhD projects. In 2019, I was awarded the President&amp;rsquo;s Medal for Outstanding Assistant Supervision for this work.</description></item></channel></rss>