<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</title><link>/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biological Metamaterials for Influencing Cell Behaviour</title><link>/research/biological-metamaterials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/biological-metamaterials/</guid><description>An electron micrograph showing silicon nanostructured with high-aspect-ratio nanostructures. I use nanostructured surfaces to study cell response to different microenvironments. I work with high-aspect-ratio nanostructures. These are surfaces patterned with tall and spiky structures.
I explore how varying design parameters such as the pitch and sharpness influences the response of different cell types. The aim is to both understand how the cell&amp;ndash;material microenvironment influences behaviour, and to explore the structure-property relationships of biomaterials.</description></item><item><title>Organic Bioelectronics for Biosensing</title><link>/research/organic-bioelectronics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/organic-bioelectronics/</guid><description>Illustration of the current range of organs being investigated by the organic bioelectronic community. I explore the use of conjugated polymers to develop a new types of biosensor and biointerfaces. My primary focus is developing a new type of biosensor for use in the early detection of breast cancer.
I use conjugated polymers (plastics that can semi-conduct electricity) to build devices that interface with cells, tissues and biological fluids.</description></item><item><title>Image-Based Cell Profiling and Data Analysis</title><link>/research/image-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/image-analysis/</guid><description>I work with large microscopy datasets and image-based cell profiling tools to automate the process of analysing hundreds of thousands of cells. I work extensively in the R programming language to develop data analysis pipelines that can clean, transform and model large datasets to generate meaningful outcomes.
Quantifying the response of cells to high-aspect-ratio nanostructures Illustration of cell-based image profiling approach. To uncover the complexity of cellular response to high-aspect-ratio nanostructures, I construct image analysis pipelines.</description></item><item><title>Energy Harvesting Organic Diodes</title><link>/research/energy-harvesting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/energy-harvesting/</guid><description>Photograph of organic diodes capable of energy harvesting at 13.56 MHz I worked as a Research Associate in the lab of Professor Henning Sirringhaus at the University of Cambridge from 2015 to 2016. My research focused on understanding and applying organic materials in the context of printed and flexible electronics. I developed organic rectifiers for use in smart packaging.
Developing energy harvesting circuits for smart packaging Energy harvesting circuits (circuits which convert radio waves into power) are found in identity cards and contactless payment systems, as well as in livestock and inventory tracking tags.</description></item><item><title>Organic Transistors and Complementary Circuits</title><link>/research/organic-transistors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/organic-transistors/</guid><description>I undertook my PhD research in the lab of Professor Alasdair Campbell at Imperial College London, from 2010 to 2014. I developed high-speed organic transistors and complementary circuits on plastic. My work used a combination of multiple types of lithography, gravure and inkjet printing.
Listen to me talk about the use of lithography and graphics arts methods in electronics on the podcast Handmade with Dr Anna Ploszajski:
Self-aligned, megahertz switching organic transistors Illustration of self-aligned transitor process.</description></item><item><title>Deceleration Beamline</title><link>/research/deceleration-beamline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/deceleration-beamline/</guid><description>As an Erasmus student, I helped simulate and construct a particle decelerator. This was a deceleration beamline for highly charged ions, as part of the Heidelberg Electron Beam Ion Trap (EBIT), at the Max-Planck-Institut für Kernphysik, Germany. I worked under the supervision of Apl. Prof. Dr. José Crespo López-Urrutia.
Understanding the origin of x-ray emission from comets Image reproduced with permission © Elsevier 2010. Figure showing the presence of charged species generated by the experiment The solar wind is a stream of highly charged ions flowing across the solar system, originating from the sun&amp;rsquo;s corona.</description></item></channel></rss>