<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Culture on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</title><link>/research-culture/</link><description>Recent content in Research Culture on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="/research-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scientists not the Science</title><link>/research-culture/scientists-not-the-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research-culture/scientists-not-the-science/</guid><description>Interviewing the Institute of Physics outreach team at The Cally Festival in 2015. I am fascinated by the way science operates. The nature, topics and goals of research are intrinsically linked to the scientists carrying out the work. Since 2015, I have been investigating these connections through my podcast Scientists not the Science.
What does it mean to be a scientist? Scientists not the Science is a podcast which interviews the people responsible for defining science as we know it: the students, staff, technicians, journal editors, journalists, engagement professionals and science comedians.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Laboratory Notebooks</title><link>/research-culture/electronic-laboratory-notebooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research-culture/electronic-laboratory-notebooks/</guid><description>An Electronic Laboratory Notebook (ELN) is a piece of software that allows lab notes to be recorded digitally, rather than using a traditional paper notebook. As a long time ELN user and System Administrator, I explored the considerations around implementing an ELN in an academic setting as part of a published review into their use.1
Ultimately, ELNs can save researchers significant amounts of time and provide a framework for better data sharing between colleagues, collaborators, and different generations of scientists.</description></item></channel></rss>