<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engagement on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</title><link>/engagement/</link><description>Recent content in Engagement on Dr Stuart G. Higgins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="/engagement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Science in the Supermarket</title><link>/engagement/super-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engagement/super-science/</guid><description>Photograph of engagement stand inside a supermarket in the West Country. Science in the Supermarket was an engagement project, funded by Imperial College London&amp;rsquo;s Societal Engagement Seed Fund to promote studying STEM subjects to young families in the West Country.
Visit the project website
Target audience The campaign targeted families with low science capital to promote the acceptance rates of students from these backgrounds into higher-education programmes. Science capital is a concept developed through the ASPIRES research project into young people’s aspirations, and is defined as “science-related qualifications, understanding, knowledge (about science and ‘how it works’), interest and social contacts (e.</description></item><item><title>STEM Outreach</title><link>/engagement/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engagement/outreach/</guid><description>Alongside my own project, Science in the Supermarket, here is a selection of projects I have been involved in.
Public talks BSA British Science Festival 2019 Daphne Oram Award Lecturer, British Science Festival Presented research at the British Science Festival 2019, as a British Science Assocation Award Lecturer
Science Communication and Public Engagement during a Global Pandemic Invited to talk to Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia (iit) alumni community about the challenges, opportunities and responsibilities of delivering public engagement during a global pandemic</description></item><item><title>Down to Earth</title><link>/engagement/down-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engagement/down-to-earth/</guid><description>I was commissioned by The Naked Scientists to produce a mini-series of episodes exploring different space-technology spin-offs, called Down to Earth. Each episode explores how a technology that was originally developed for space exploration became useful in life on the planet. Episodes were broadcast in the UK on BBC Radio and internationally as part of the main radio show.
Links to online episodes Launch of Down to Earth mini-series How Space Science Gave Us&amp;hellip; Airbags, 27/06/2017</description></item></channel></rss>